Be ready to answer to my sword of justice.
Osman!
I was born with a sword in my hand.
You cannot scare me with death!
We will either die or kill you all!
Do your best!
The one who is born with
a sword, dies by the sword.
I will teach you all of this
while I cut your head off.
For the Holy Roman Empire!
For the Holy Roman Empire! Alps!
Alps!
Attack!
O Healer.
They will recover God willing.
God willing.
Thanks to Allah.
The antidote is working, mother.
Good, thanks to Allah, my daughter.
-Mother...
What if my brother can't
take the antidote to my father?
My daughter. Think of good things
for good things to happen, alright?
We found the antidote thanks to Allah.
He will take it there in time, God willing.
Sisters! Come on
Bring lots of bottles!
This antidote will be sent everywhere, come on!
My Allah, make the wind a
wing and help Alaeddin go there.
God willing.
God willing he will give the antidote to my Osman.
Aameen.
Thank you.
He is about to die!
Don't let go!
Victory is ours!
Until your last drop of blood!
Brothers! This enemy is different! Stay strong!
Seems they ate their food well.
Don't let them defeat you, brothers!
Allah is the Greatest!
Osman Bey fell down!
My Osman!
Osman is on the ground!
Alps...
I am here, my Bey! I will save you!
My Bey
Close the door.
Come here.
So... what happened?
What did you learn? Where is Osman?
I don't know where Osman is.
But Alaeddin went to give the antidote to him.
Where did he go?
I don't know.
You said he was lying half-dead.
Nobody is saying anything.
Yes..
Alaeddin is gone.
Osman is gone.
But if he recovers and comes back...
...we may not get this chance again.
Until Claudius and the emperor's army arrives...
...we will destroy Mudurnu from the inside.
What should we do?
We will kill Bala.
Now listen to me carefully.
I am here, my Bey! I'm here!
Thanks to Allah!
The antidote!
Stop that man! He brought the antidote!
Father!
Come on!
Stop!
Turgut Ghazi!
Antidote!
Father!
Come on! Come on!
Osman!
Osman... Osman...
Come on. You will be alright.
Drink this.
-Drink this.
-My Bey. My Bey!
My Bey. My Bey!
O Healer.
Sofia, you are late!
Osman is still alive!
He's going to die with my sword!
Soldiers, attack!
Attack!
My Bey! Alps, protect Osman Bey!
You will be alright.
Father!
Father! Father.
Father, are you alright? Are you alright?
Get up, my Bey.
He's good.
-Praise be.
-Come on, my Bey. Come on.
Come on.
We're retreating.
Come on, come on.
Osman! Don't run away!
Faithless dogs!
Allah is the greatest!
Come on, warriors! Come on!
Stand up!
-Go after him!
-Come on!
We can't catch him.
Osman predicts every move we can make.
It will be the emperor's decision.
Allah Almighty speaks the truth.
My Allah, please heal my Osman.
Let them come back safely.
Sofia says hello, Bala.
Traitor.
Snake put you among us, huh?
You survived the poison but you'll die soon.
I won't kill you before you speak.
-Speak.
-Stupid Eleni.
You're going to die today, Bala.
Speak!
I will tell you.
Who? Who?
Mother.
Sisters are fainted.
Sisters, help!
Die, you snake.
Who? Who put you among us?
Tell me.
-Mother, your hand is bleeding.
-Bring the healer!
This snake can't die! Come on, speak.
Tell me who put you among us.
What have you done, Yigit Bey?
She was going to tell everything.
I saw sisters and alps fainted at the door and...
..I saw blood on your hand...
...so I didn't know what to do, Bala Hatun.
-I could have made her fall with a slap!
-You are right.
Take her dead body away.
I don't know what to say, Bala Hatun.
For Allah's sake...
If something happened to you
...how could I explain it to Osman Bey?
It's not good but what happened happened.
You had your reasons.
Mother, your hand doesn't look well.
Let's get it examined.
-Alright.
-Welcome, my Bey.
-Osman Bey, welcome!
-Thank you.
-Osman.
Are you alright?
I'm fine. Don't worry.
-Alaaddin brought the antidote.
-Thanks to Allah.
My Bey, where are you coming from like this?
We defeated the reinforcement
units of the emperor, Koca Bey.
My Bey, did you fight although you were poisoned?
Don't worry, Yigit Bey.
As long as I keep breathing, I will never stop.
Praise be, Praise be.
My Bey, if you want to rest...
We only rest when we die, Bala.
Let's gather the war council!
As you order, my Bey.
As my Bey orders.
Turgut Ghazi.
You're coming with me.
Only a few knew that the army would come.
How could Osman know about it?
I don't know but I will find
out what he is planning.
Yigit.
Don't you suspect him?
No.
I'm sure it wasn't him.
You spoke surely about the poison saying they
could never find the antidote but they did.
Osman will recover.
Osman survived the poison.
But he can't survive the
death I prepared for him.
You take the soldiers to Iznik.
I will meet Yigit and find out what happened.
Neither this water nor all the
rivers can put out the fire in my heart.
Before those two demons die, we
can't get rid of the dark clouds over us.
Well... Things would have gone
terrible without you Turgut Ghazi.
Thank you, Osman.
Our move has saved us for now.
We repelled their army, but...
...we won't be safe until
we find the traitor among us.
He's such a traitor that he
manages to cover his tracks.
A jackal disguising as a wolf.
What are you thinking of?
I think...
...he's breathing the same air with us.
Right next to us.
During a war, I can't blame
the Beys for such thing.
We need every single alp. I can't do that.
Before the spy is exposed,
all of our plans will fail.
Tell me.
What's in your mind?
What are you planning to expose the traitor?
They'll think the state is sleeping.
But the state never sleeps.
We'll see who is the traitor and who is the fool.
Let them think we're sleeping.
When it's time, when they make a mistake,
...their heads will fall at our feet.
-For sure.
-Do I have permission, my Bey?
Come in.
Beys are ready, my Bey.
Attention! Osman Bey!
-Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you too.
Praise be.
The poison's effect is gone.
Allah protected you for your
family and for the state, Osman Bey.
Thank you, Koca Bey, thank you.
Thank you.
Byzantium which is a threat to our existence...
Even if we pushed them back for
now, we have not yet defeated them.
The Emperor's guards will
come at us while we are struggling.
That is why I want to ask something, Osman Bey.
Did the head of our state see
our mistake or weakness that...
...he went into battle without telling us?
My Bey, we said the way and the target are one.
-But when you went without calling us...
-I fully trust my Beys.
But hard times require quick decisions.
Since we don't know where
the enemy will attack from...
...it was necessary for you to stay in Mudurnu.
We went in secret and pushed back their armies.
Thank you, Osman Bey.
My Bey, what should we do now?
Whatever we do, we must be quick.
What is your order?
No, speed is for horses.
A wolf always waits for the right time.
Now if the enemy attacks us..
...it will be from Mudurnu or Goynuk.
These places are both on the road to
Iznik and on their most important lands.
So my decision is this.
We will wait for them in Mudurnu.
Beys, gather all your men inside Mudurnu.
We will face the enemy with all our strength.
Wherever Claudius attacks from, he
must pass through Mudurnu's borders.
When he shows himself, we will stop him, my Bey.
We will gather all the Alps in Mudurnu.
A big storm will break out.
But we will not die without fighting.
As you order, my Bey.
You may leave.
What happened?
My Bey.
-Yes.
Come here.
You check around.
Claudius wants to see me.
Bring my horse.
The poison weakened the
strength of the Alps, Koca Bey.
The Emperor's army is about to attack.
The Turk's fate is written by war, Hasan Bey.
I'm not afraid of war, Koca Bey.
But I don't want to lose either.
You heard Osman Bey.
My Alps in Goynuk are alright.
Tell Yigit.
He will help you with Mudurnu's defense.
Until the Alps come from my
tribe, it's good to be cautious.
You thought well, Hasan Bey.
May it be easy. Thank you.
Thank you Koca Bey.
If anyone asks about me, tell them
I'll be back after checking the horses.
Come on.
Yigit Bey.
Where are you going?
Bring my horse.
Come on!
Hasan Bey.
Cerkutay Bey.
I know your pain.
But I have nothing to say to you.
You don't even know what shame is, huh, Hasan?
Alps, stop!
My Hatun was martyred.
Many families were torn apart because of you.
Cerkutay Bey, you heard about the poison.
Those dastards planned everything.
What were you going to do?
But look, you're still here.
You're still breathing.
Enough
What do you want, huh?
Do you want my life?
Take it.
What are you doing?
Stop!
What happened to you, huh?
Does doing this in front of our people suit you?
Osman Bey will hear you now.
This is not over.
You will pay for it.
What happened to your hand?
It's nothing. I'll tell you.
What do you mean nothing?
That helper girl of Yigit Bey, Eleni.
The girl who came from Goynuk.
Right?
She was a spy for Sofia. She tried to kill me.
If she was talking to Sofia, she
might have been a part of this betrayal.
It would have been
good if we could make her speak,
but Yigit Bey killed
her at the last moment.
Tell me what happened.
Claudius
Osman is waiting for you, take precautions...
You said Osman was going to die?
You said he was poisoned?
He destroyed half of my army.
He escaped from the claws of Azrael.
He should not have been able to fight.
How did he learn about the emperor's guards?
Why didn't you tell me?
He left secretly. I didn't know.
He suspects that there is a spy among us.
Claudius, our fate is the same.
Luck is on their side, but they will die.
What about Bala?
She is alive. Osman is taking
precautions against your armies.
What precautions?
He thinks you will attack the Mudurnu line.
So he is sending all his Alps to Mudurnu.
But these precautions won't save
him from the death written in his fate.
My beautiful sisters. Our father is alright.
He will be better when he rests, God willing.
My Hatun, do you see?
They don't know their father at all.
Didn't I tell you not to be afraid?
We are daughters of Osman Bey. We never fear.
But of course, we were worried, father.
We could not help it, father.
Well well...
A rose blooms, and the garden becomes beautiful.
A girl grows up, and the
homeland becomes beautiful.
As long as you are with me...
...no one can defeat me.
No one.
Come on now, go sit.
Sit..
Ah Ulgen, how will we get used to your absence?
See... Death is always beside us.
We learned to live with it,
and we will continue to learn.
May Allah show her mercy.
Ulgen has now reached Allah.
Of course people feel sorry
for those who pass away.
But they feel even more sorry
for the ones who are left behind.
The deceased reach Allah,
but the living feel longing, father.
Of course, of course.
Cerkutay and Ghazi.
We shouldn't leave them alone.
I invited them here to share our meal.
But Cerkutay Bey wants to be alone, father.
Let them be alone for now. But
later, let them know we are with them.
Step back...
Ghazi..
Cerkutay!
I'll kill you...
Again?
What am I going to do now?
My Allah... Help me.
My Allah, help me...
They left me helpless and
miserable, Turgut Ghazi.
They took my heart out of my body.
They left me alone with this innocent child.
What am I going to do now?
What cold water should I drink
to put out the fire in my heart?
How will I resist without
my wife, without my Hatun?
What am I going to do?
Our destiny is only in the power of Allah.
Death and life are only in His hands, Cerkutay.
Take it out.
Take my heart out, Turgut Ghazi.
I... I cannot endure this pain again.
What am I going to do, how will I endure this?
By believing, Cerkutay.
By believing
You know that...
...we will all go to our real homeland one day.
This world is a test for all of us, my son.
Pain and suffering will end when that time comes.
Do not..
...do not fall into rebellion.
It's Allah Who gives and takes.
Look there.
You have a great boy growing up.
Despair would never suit you.
Pull yourself together.
My brother Bamsi once looked after you.
Now I will help you.
Everything will be alright, boy.
Everything will be alright.
I will take Mudurnu and
Goynuk back from vile Osman.
He knows about the army.
He'll take more measures.
Definitely.
But I will hit him in such a
spot that he will lose everything.
What did you learn, Claudius?
My emperor, Osman has
gathered his army in Mudurnu.
He's taking measures there.
As we predicted.
-How did he know about the army?
-Yigit doesn't know either.
He said Osman left secretly.
He suspects that there is a traitor among them.
So he’s more cautious these days.
He'll do everything to defend Mudurnu and Goynuk.
He will tire our army and then attack.
Then... While he is expecting
us in Mudurnu and Goynuk,
...we should capture Kayi Tribe.
We'll hit him in the unexpected spot, huh?
If he loses his tribe, he will lose
the trust of all his beys and people.
When he loses his tribe, we will
isolate Osman from the others.
So it will be easier to
capture Mudurnu and Goynuk.
And nobody will know this until tomorrow.
Even not the army.
You'll tell them on the way.
Yes, my Emperor.
Great Emperor, the army are ready.
Waiting for your orders.
Let them wait for my decision.
Claudius and Sofia will tell
them about the target in Akcebe.
They should have a good rest tonight.
Of course.
Do I have permission, my Bey?
-Come in, Alaaddin.
My Bey, the sick are regaining
strength thanks to Allah.
-Thank Allah.
-Good. Alaaddin.
Go to our tribe immediately.
As you order, my Bey.
We'll leave before the azan.
You're still thinking about
the battlefield, Osman.
What do you think?
The battle isn't in the field but in minds, Bala.
We've defeated the heathens
for now. But they won't stop.
The traitor among us will tell them our
troops are in Mudurnu and Goynuk now.
You say they will leave Mudurnu and
Goynuk for now and march to other targets.
Where do you think they'll attack, my Bey?
Kayi Tribe which they think is unprotected.
But that will be their death.
My Bey.
Pardon me but what if they don't
get deceived but make another move?
The spy in the council.
He only knows what I said.
So they will think we are
taking measures in Mudurnu.
In fact, all of our weapons are in Kayi Tribe.
So the enemy will think
our forces are in Mudurnu.
But they will walk into the trap.
Then we should wait for the
enemy to come into our trap.
There is a traitor among us.
Beys will know nothing.
Only we know about this.
Alps are standing ready, Koca Bey.
Mudurnu has become a shield of alps, for sure.
The hammer swords of the enemy will be
broken on that anvil-like shield, Hasan Bey.
God willing, Koca Bey.
Yigit Bey... Where is Yigit Bey?
Checking the alps.
Why?
We should take measures in case of
another riot Christian people may start.
His odalisque Eleni turned out to be a betrayer.
People may be suspicious about him.
Keep him away from this, Hasan Bey.
Okay, Koca Bey.
I'll give information to Osman
Bey and then take measures.
None of Osman Bey's alps is here.
Why is that?
-We'll talk to Osman Bey.
-Osman Bey isn't here.
Not here?
Where is Osman Bey going?
In the name of Allah,
the merciful, the compassionate.
Oghuz, empty the carts in the square.
As you order, Alaaddin Bey.
Alps, you go take your positions.
As you order, my Bey.
Fatma, let's start the preparations quickly.
-May your work be easy.
-Thank you.
Sisters, are you ready?
Let me see. Show me.
Praise be.
Come on, alps! Come on!
Hurry, come on
Come on.
Open it.
Good.
Here we go.
Shahzade Alaaddin.
Boy.
What are you doing here?
The enemy are coming, my
Shahzade. I want to fight too.
Praise be. Praise be.
The brave of my tribe listen to me.
A sword cuts a heart out.
Some words require a heart to say.
We need to stand united during a war.
But your duty in this war is
defending your own family, alright?
-Yes.
-Good boy.
My boy.
My boy, family is the most precious treasure.
You protect your family and
we protect our tribe, alright?
-Yes.
Let me kiss you.
My brave boy. Praise be.
Well, hatun...
As long as everybody, the elder and
the young, loves homeland so much,
...Turks will make history.
The whole world will be a path
for them to follow, thank Allah.
Thank Allah.
May Allah give us children to run in
that path for our cause, Alaaddin Ali.
God willing, hatun.
God willing.
-Here we go.
Well... Come on.
Sir, Osman's Shahzade and
daughters have gone to their tribe.
They are just a few. And there
are only ordinary people in the tribe.
It's good that Alaaddin is in the tribe.
Today, Osman is going to
lose both his tribe and children.
Well, Poena...
Who you chose instead
of me will bring your death.
Although you raised her, she is a Turk.
It's not surprising that she's a fool.
She is a Turk.
The day she chose Bala
and Osman, she killed Poena.
I'm going to kill her myself.
Good.
Today is the vengeance day.
The day when Osman is going to writhe in pain.
Let's get started. Come on.
Come on.
Fatma Hatun.
Sister. Oguz Bey wants to tell you something.
I was going to ask if you
need anything or need help.
No, thank you. Come on Halime.
But we need help.
There is really a lot of work here, sister.
I will help with the work
here, you stay here, huh?
Halime.
I am sorry...
We can do it but you know
better what to do, Fatma Hatun.
Guide us.
I do. But my brother gave the duty to you.
Now I should not interfere.
As soon as you came back to the
tribe, you became yourself again, Kayi...
I mean, Fatma Hatun, it
seems our hostility continues.
No. Why would there be a
hostility between us, Oguz Bey?
But I should warn you. My brother will
not care whether you are crazy or not.
If he sees something wrong,
he answers accordingly.
Gather those arrows, they
should all be in an order.
I am again the crazy one, thanks to Allah.
But you started it. If you didn't
talk, I would have kept walking.
No. I have no complaint.
If you want, you can call me
crazy until evening. I accept it.
My Shahzade.
Claudius and Sofia. They
are coming with their armies.
Dastards.
Oguz, take precautions.
If they are coming, they will pay for it.
Kayi tribe will now become Byzantine land.
Battering ram!
That Osman you trust won't be able to save you!
You came to your death, dogs.
Come on, brothers!
Ya Allah!
Attack!
Allah is the Greatest!
Attack Alps!
Today is the day of shahada
but we will not surrender!
Devils... you will not win
Allah is the Greatest!
Alps! Stand tall!
Alps! Step back!
Allah is the Greatest!
Alps! We are retreating!
Bring the shields!
You won't be able to escape!
Turks, your end has come!
I will take all your heads
and send them to Osman!
Don't worry, we will send him to hell too.
You are the people of hell.
But I will be the one to send you there.
Hristo.
Tell me Hristo.
What is the emperor's new target?
The emperor will attack the Kayi
tribe with all his power, Osman Bey.
Just as you said, they fell for your game.
What is your order now, my Osman?
That place will be their grave.
Both of you are no longer human, you are demons.
You deserve death!
Traitor!
They call me Solgur Agha.
Whoever sets his eyes on the shadow
of the Turk is destined to be destroyed.
All oppressors must know this!
Even if the jackal speaks
first, I always say the last word.
You planned a game.
But you fell into a trap.
Now it is time to pay for what you have done.
Where will you escape now, Sofia?
I swear, we will make you pay
for everything you have done to us.
Alps! Attack!
Poena..
Not Poena, Halime!
My little angel of revenge..
Allah is the Greatest!
Today, you will get your
share from Solgur Agha's furor.
Allah is the Greatest!
Sofia!
We will either run away or die here!
It's not over yet, Claudius!
Come on!
The end of those who attack Osman
Bey's tribe is death, you dastards.
Attack, valiants!
These demons will die here today!
Allah is the Greatest!
Sofia! Yunus! Give me the bow and the arrows!
Osman, Osman... They are running away!
They cannot go anywhere!
They will die today!
Alps! Bring the horses!
Come on!
Halime.
Halime!
Halime, are you alright?
Get up! Are you alright?
-I am alright.
My Halime, you have just recovered.
Go to your tent now.
The sword... Here, take my sword...
Come on, my rose! Come on!
Osman was going to wait for them in Mudurnu.
He played a game.
How did that happen?
What are we going to do now, my Bey?
I don't know what we are going to do.
Won't the enemy attack
the Mudurnu line, Koca Bey?
Why do you think Osman
Bey called the Beys to his tribe?
There is something strange...
But I don't know what it is.
We will find out once we talk to Osman Bey.
Okay.
Claudius!
Sofia, you go!
I can deal with them alone!
No!
Sofia. There will be no
betrayal this time, believe me!
Go now! Go!
Come on!
Sofia.
Come here Sofia!
Come on!
Foolish Claudius...
Your foolish bravery made you face me, huh?
Finally, it is time to face each other, Osman.
I really don't want your
dirty body to lie on this land.
But... But you will die.
Soldier!
Sofia!
Sofia.
Go Sofia...
Slowly.
Just wait.
Get your hand off.
Both that traitor and you are going to die.
So you know.
But you'll never find out who he is.
You think so?
Huh?
Get up.
Who?
You'll tell me.
You say so?
It's weird that you're trying to get information
from a man who is going to die shortly.
Both you and that traitor
will taste my sword of justice.
To make an example. I'll kill
you in the square of Kayi Tribe.
Get up.
Move.
Osman..
...is taking Claudius to his tribe.
-What if he gives your name to Osman, my Bey?
-No way.
Then my grave will be prepared
next to Claudius' grave, Seyit.
Come on, alps!
Keep swinging the glorious swords of Turks!
Beat them all!
Come on!
Whoever attempts to kill us ends up in hell!
The enemy will get ruined!
The state will always prevail!
Allah is the greatest!
What's going on here, Turgut Ghazi?
Who is attacking the tribe?
We ruined the plan of the heathens.
I will explain everything Koca Bey. Don't worry.
Where is your brother Yigit?
I'm here, Turgut Ghazi.
I'm here.
I got shocked like my brother.
You didn't inform us.
Osman Bey is coming!
Osman Bey is bringing the head of the snake.
-Murderer!
-Kill him!
Move!
Murderer!
You took my hatun from me, you dastard.
-It's the day of reckoning.
-Hush, Ghazi.
Dastard!
My Bey will take care of this.
You have done terrible things.
The back of Kayi is full of dagger
marks of you and people like you!
You killed the men of many families.
You slaughtered many hatuns!
This is a war, Osman.
A war.
Someone loses.
Someone wins.
This time, you won.
And I lost.
But it isn't over.
Even after centuries,
this war will never be over.
You're going to kill me now.
But Rome will keep
attacking you with all his wrath!
We have enough land to bury you all!
Whoever is born with a sword dies with a sword.
I told you.
I said I would make you learn that...
...while your head was falling on the ground.
Now it's time for justice.
My Beys! My alps!
This dog and people like him
are neither the first nor the last!
People like him are waiting
to attack us in the dark caves!
But we will attack before they do!
And we'll stick these swords into their chests!
Allah is the greatest!
Halime.
Brother, I adorned your sword. Do you like it?
Halime. Are you alright, my sister?
-Brother.
-Yes?
Have you been carrying the
adornment on your sword for years?
How...
Do you remember that?
I do.
You, sister, father, mother and everything.
What are you saying, my sister?
Praise be.
Thanks to my Allah.
I told you.
I said everything would be
alright when drugs lost their effect.
What's going on here?
Come.
Sister.
-Yes?
Why did you pour sand on my head?
-What sand, Halime?
-Just sand.
You used to pour sand on my
head. And they went in my hair.
My mother got angry but you...
Halime, you remember...
She doesn't remember
good things but it's alright.
The snaked called Sofia couldn't win again.
-She will never win.
-Ever.
Well..
Let's go and give our parents the great news.
-Let's go.
-Oh my dear sister.
Let's go.
Deliver this letter to Emperor Andronikos.
Let him know that Claudius
died with his soldiers.
I relied on Claudius.
But he failed, Seyit.
He couldn't do it.
He lost.
Yet I will never give up.
What's in your mind, my Bey?
Iron is forged with hammers, Seyit.
I will talk to Sofia.
I will ally with her.
The hammer here is Sofia.
And she will finish Osman off.
And I will get rid of this tent.
...and own the beylic chair I deserve.
Come on, let's go.
Deliver the news quickly.
Don't get yourself exposed.
Here we go.
Where are you going?
Yigit Bey is sending me to his
tribe. I have things to tell people.
Where is your Bey? What
are you going to tell people?
Get down here.
Is your Bey sending a letter to his people?
I'm just doing what I'm told, Turgut Ghazi.
You filthy-blooded ones.
You are the traitors.
Now you will tell me everything you have done.
Or I will skin you alive.
Osman, we killed one enemy
but the other one is still outside.
We can't be at ease before Sofia dies.
Our alps are searching everywhere, my Bey.
The borders of Bursa are being held too.
We'll find her, God willing.
That snake will curl under a stone, Boran.
You don't know her as well as I do.
Bala, don't worry.
Which enemy has managed to get rid of us so far?
We'll find her. We will. We will.
What's the matter, Turgut Ghazi?
The traitor is Yigit, Osman.
This jackal told me everything.
He made a deal with Claudius
and Sofia for gold and land.
Is that so?
Yigit is the traitor, huh?
May you be cursed.
While you beheaded Claudius, I
watched all the Beys one by one.
With the fear that Claudius
might expose his name,
...Yigit tried to hide himself slowly.
That was the moment when
I realized he was the traitor.
Look at me. Look!
Where is he now?
He's gone to meet Sofia, my Bey.
My Bey... What are you thinking about?
Yigit will bring Sofia to us.
They won't die easily.
Now listen to me carefully.
Sofia.
It's me, Yigit.
Claudius told me about this place.
We are on the same side.
Claudius.
Right.
Where is he?
He died.
Osman killed him.
Right...
Yes.
Osman... I swear, I will kill you
and Bala with my own hands.
Sofia.
If you allow me, I want to
share your oath with you.
Claudius died but my cause is not over.
Claudius trusted you.
He was right.
What?
We will set a trap against Osman together.
You will inform me about every step he takes.
Where is he now?
He is in the tribe.
He is celebrating his victory.
And Beys are praising him.
Especially my disgraceful brother...
They will all pay for it.
For revenge..
Yes?
Will you risk everything?
Including your brother?
Don't worry about it.
I will kill that old man with my own hands.
My only dream is to sit on
the seat he stole from me.
You will get more than your dream.
I will kill Osman and Bala
and you'll kill Koca Bey.
And then...
...all the tribes will obey you.
And you will obey the Byzantine.
Now..
Go back to the tribe and keep following them.
Alright.
Alright, I am leaving
Tomorrow, we will hold a meeting.
I will announce the decisions that
will expand our lands to the Beys.
Everything will be ready, my Bey, don't worry.
Thank you, thank you.
What is this, my Osman?
Alaeddin gave this to me.
It will be applied to the wound on your hand.
Alaeddin did not bring it himself
but gave it to his father, huh?
Look at him...
While dealing with all these problems...
...are you worried about this small
wound on my hand. Dark Osman?
You have fallen into my heart.
If even your nail gets hurt, my heart aches.
Here.
This needs to be applied often.
Often.
Come on... Cover it.
Hold it here.
Hold it there.
It used to hurt, but now it's gone.
Look...
What is your concern?
Sofia.
Don't Bala.
Don't look at me like that, Osman.
What if our plan fails? What if it doesn't work?
Don't you trust me?
-I'll find Sofia.
-When did I ever not trust you, my Dark Osman?
If they say there is death behind
this door, I won't leave you alone.
I'll hold your hand and walk with you.
Don't worry.
I will become a shield for you...
And I will not let anyone do anything to you.
It's not about me, Osman. It's about us.
The one we face is a snake after all.
We can never know what she is
going to do. You know her the best.
Sofia doesn't have much time left.
I will make such a plan that neither Yigit
nor Sofia will live long, don't worry.
May Allah help us, my Bey.
May our home and tribe
be filled with joy and peace.
Aameen, my Bala. Aameen.
What did you do?
Did you send the news to the emperor?
I did, my Bey.
To stop Osman's advance...
...the Emperor will take precautions.
These precautions will open
the way to the seat for me, Seyit.
That way might open before
the precautions, my Bey.
How?
I heard from the Alps.
Osman Bey and Bala Hatun will leave
early morning to welcome the migrants.
Allah..
You gave me such good news.
My lion. My lion.
They think that by killing
Claudius, they found peace.
But this comfort will bring them death.
They don't know. Sofia is in Bursa.
Come on then.
Let her hear this news too. Go.
As you order, my Bey.
Tomorrow..
Sofia will kill Osman.
And I will kill my brother under
whose shadow I rotted for years.
The time has come for the prey
and the celebration to be mine.
Show it to your brother. Come on Melikshah!
Come on Alparslan.
Show your brother.
O people! May everyone hear it!
Osman Bey is holding a council.
Do you know why this council is held?
Are you curious about the council, kids?
Yes.
Come and sit with me. Come.
Come.
We hold councils because decisions
for the state are made at the council.
Talking, consulting, and being
together are the virtues of the Beys.
This meeting is the state's council.
The most important issues and state
affairs are discussed at the council.
As they say, when the council
is held, the tribe grows bigger.
Who holds the council?
The head of the state holds the
council. And that is Osman Bey.
Does Bala Hatun attend the council?
Of course she does. The
lion's wife is also a lion.
And she stands next to her Bey.
I heard from my mother. A state is founded
with the union of a Hatun and a Bey.
Why is food eaten at the council?
Our ancestor Oguz set this tradition.
He said that at the council
the Bey's meal shall be eaten.
State words shall be spoken.
That meal is blessed.
He ordered to follow and
celebrate this tradition.
This is why the Bey's
table is set at the council.
Everyone eats and drinks
and then speaks their words.
Can we join the council?
Of course you can. Of course.
You will grow up and become Beys and Hatuns.
Then all of you will take
your place at the council.
The coming generations
are the guarantee of the state.
We will entrust this state to you.
We founded the state.
From now on you will carry the banner.
Tell me now.
Are you ready for this sacred duty?
We are ready.
Praise be to you.
Praise be.
The future of Islam...
...will rise on the
shoulders of brave and
tradition-knowing generations
like you, God willing.
God willing Turgut Gazi.
Praise be to you.
Praise be.
My Bala, our number has
grown a lot with the migrants.
Our burden is heavier now.
Now we need to be more
careful. We will work hard.
We will feed the hungry and make
those who do not have work, work, my Bey.
We will bring an order with
justice and unity, God willing.
God willing, God willing.
This order will develop Mudurnu and Goynuk.
We will build new tribes and new homes.
Every new land is written not only
on the soil but also on us, Osman.
The migrants come with hope,
and we welcome them with effort.
When these two come together,
the state begins to take root.
Taking root is not only done with sword, Bala.
Of course, we have brave Alps and powerful Beys.
But the actual matter is to be a family.
We will encourage our men
and sisters to build families.
We will build their homes together, God willing.
God willing, God willing.
Being a family is not just
about living in a home.
Being a family is about
building half of the state.
My Bala.
Do you remember my words?
Alaca, Osman Bey wants a race.
Look at me, Iltutan.
Alaca is too old.
Don't be hard on her.
Oh look at him!
Alaca, Osman Bey seems
to have forgotten your skills.
-Let's remind him.
-I haven't forgotten anything.
Alright then.
Whoever loves most runs fastest.
How long?
I know the destination best. Follow me.
Let's go, girl!
I will ruin every moment you laugh!
I swear to God that I will
destroy both you and your wife.
Soldiers.
We'll follow them. Come on!
Today, everything will be over.
Sofia is going to kill Osman.
Why did you organize this hunting trip, my Bey?
Do you think Sofia can do this on her own?
She has to.
Osman is going to be hunted by
Sofia and my brother Koca Bey by me.
Are you going to kill Koca Bey, my Bey?
Tell the alps to be ready.
Peace be upon you.
Peace be upon you too, brother.
Come here, brother.
My brave brother.
Are you ready for hunting, brother?
You know... Hunting is
my thing. I'm always ready.
I know.
Even during the famines, the cauldron
would boil with what you hunted.
Those days are over.
The wolf has got too old
but his eyes are still sharp.
I can still hit the bullseye.
You can, brother.
-Give me.
-The arrows.
After you, brother.
You aren't so bad, Alaca.
Not bad.
He says we aren't so bad, Alaca.
Come.
We've waited for this day for so long, Osman.
It will be history, huh?
Yes, we will keep our promises.
Today you smile differently.
You smile differently.
These eyes only smile for you, my Brunet Osman.
I don't believe that.
What's that supposed to mean?
You used to smile like this when you saw me.
But now you do it only
when you see your children.
Do you envy your children, Osman?
When I look at them, I see you.
Your part in each of them.
That's why I smile like that.
When Halime came, your eyes were shining.
Don't you ever lose that smile.
Don't you ever lose these smiling eyes.
I'm sorry. Today is your last day together.
That isn't possible while I'm here.
Both of you are going to die today.
It's you who is going under the ground today.
Peace be upon you, red witch.
Sofia's soldiers are going to fall.
Now what, Sofia?
I'm going to kill you.
Soldiers, attack!
I wanted to join Osman Bey's
council with what I hunted, but...
...there isn't anything to hunt today, I guess.
There is.
And old one to hunt!
-What are you doing, Yigit?
-Don't come closer!
Today you are the huntee and I'm the hunter.
Are you going to kill me?
Why?
Why would you do this vile thing?
I'm tired of withering in your shadow.
Withering?
I have a share in everything in your tribe!
And what do I have in my hands?
Nothing!
A huge nothing!
From which poisonous spring did you drink
water and let the demon capture your heart?
It seems I raised a snake beside me!
I'm going to kill you, brother.
And I will take what is mine.
Release your arrow! Come on, kill me! Kill me!
Dastard!
Shoot me!
Turgut Ghazi... How did you...
You jackal disguising as a wolf!
Your mask has fallen.
Your betrayal has got exposed.
Alps, attack.
Dastards!
Turgut Ghazi!
Seyit!
Your poisonous snake.
You aren't my brother anymore!
This dastard didn't betray only you, Koca Bey.
He also betrayed Osman Bey
by collaborating with Byzantine.
Did you even do that, dastard?
His treason will be punished by Osman Bey.
How can I appear before Osman
Bey with this shame now, Turgut Ghazi?
Habils won't be blamed for
the things Qabils did, Koca Bey.
The shame belongs to this
dastard who desired mortal things.
Move.
Allah is the greatest!
Byzantine heathens, death
is the only salvation for you!
Today I'm going to win, Osman.
You can't do anything while I'm here.
I took an oath, Sofia. I'll make you
pay for all the sufferings you caused.
We'll be even, Bala.
For the last time.
I'll make you pay for the
sufferings you gave my daughter.
I loved her more than you did. She's my daughter.
You loved her?
You made her bleed!
You tried to kill her.
No easy death for you!
I called you snake but you aren't.
You are a scorpion.
A filthy scorpion.
There is stinging in your nature.
Bala.
Bala, leave her.
Bala, leave her. Come on.
I will punish her at the tents.
It's time for you.
Take her.
Red demon, your death is here.
-Are you alright?
-I'm good.
I'm good
My dear.
My baby.
Look.
It's spring, my baby.
Flowers have blossomed.
They smell beautiful.
But none of them smells as beautiful as you.
Nothing can take your place, my baby.
Nothing can.
Gonca.
You sew the daisies, right?
You see how fast they grew up. Alaaddin?
Yet our daughter will never grow up.
You see how fast the daisies grew up. Alaaddin?
I see, Gonca. I see.
Daisies are the witnesses of our love, huh?
I wanted our love to embrace our baby.
Her parents are always here for her.
I wanted her to know that.
I miss her so much.
Alaaddin, I miss her so much. What will I do?
I miss our baby so much.
So do I.
We'll meet our anger in the afterlife, Gonca.
We will meet, my baby.
Alaaddin, I'm so scared of
going through the same suffering.
I know.
I know that feeling.
My Allah will make all our fears disappear.
When the time comes, we will have children too.
They will grow our love day by day.
We will have children, right?
They will run and play
like others, right, Alaeddin?
Sure... Sure they will.
Look, we suffered a lot.
My Allah...
My Allah will grant us the greatest joys.
Don't worry.
God willing my Alaeddin... God willing.
My daughter...
The daisy of her father...
Your father is here...
In the name of Allah,
the merciful, the compassionate.
My beautiful daughter.
My daisy...
Osman.
Osman killed Claudius.
Since Sofia did not come, he captured her too.
Osman.
His end will not come before
we turn the frontiers into hell.
Get ready.
We are returning to Constantinople.
Without wasting time, I will gather the Senate.
I will strike him from the place he least
expects, and we will become Osman's hell.
His hell!
My Bey caught Sofia!
You will die, demon!
Sofia..
Justice will finally be provided, sister.
Traitor!
You dastard!
Infidel! You will die!
Walk!
Come on!
Soon, you will pay for
everything you have done, Sofia.
O, people of Kayi.
The day we will take revenge from Sofia,
who has caused us so much pain, has come.
Poena, forgive me...
My anger blinded my eyes.
I never wanted to hurt you.
I would never do that.
You will never be forgiven, Sofia.
You will die the way you deserve!
I am not talking to you Bala!
My little bird...
Will you forgive me?
This woman destroyed many families!
She left many mothers
childless, many valiants graveless!
This woman brought darkness,
cruelty, and betrayal to these lands.
I wanted you to see...
...and know this.
In Kayi tribe, justice is not served in secret!
Whoever oppresses others
will pay for it in this square.
Uncle..
What is happening, brothers?
Is that him?
This is the traitor who spied for Claudius.
He told me everything one by one.
Is that so?
Koca Bey.
Don't bow your head...
I am ashamed to look at your face, Osman Bey.
I brought this traitor dog to your presence.
Now I am leaving.
No, stop!
We..
We know who is innocent and who is guilty.
Stand tall.
Forgive me, my Bey, I did it,
but you show your greatness.
Shut up you coward dog!
At least die with honor.
Traitor!
How many coins did you sell us for?
I didn't sell anyone, my Bey.
Claudius threatened me with my life.
So many innocent people lost their lives.
So many Turks' blood was spilled.
Forgive me.
No
The state is as great as the
punishment it gives to a traitor.
For those who betray their state and nation,
the shadow of this holy banner is forbidden.
Your punishment is this sword that goes
in clean and comes out covered in blood.
Here..
Whoever betrays us will
meet the same fate as this dog.
Now it's your turn.
I bear witness that there is none
worthy of worship except Allah....
...and I bear witness that Muhammad
is His servant and Messenger.
You snake..
Devil! You're playing games again, Sofia.
I understood when I was at hell's threshold.
No revenge can save my soul.
I know it's too late for that.
I found the right path.
Father, this snake is playing a game again.
Look at me.
The decision is yours, Osman Bey.
Take her to the caged tent.
Take her!
You played your game again, Sofia.
No more games, Gonca.
I don't believe you, Sofia.
You're playing games again.
Maybe you changed me.
Walk, Sofia, come on. Come on, walk.
So my eyes have seen that
the red witch became a Muslim...
That witch may be lying out of fear.
I expect anything from this Sofia snake.
Osman Bey will make the right decision.
We all know what she did to us.
Now she says she believes Islam.
Tell me.
What do you think?
That snake left us helpless.
Doesn't her faith look like the Pharaoh's faith?
What if she is lying again?
Pharaoh repented but he was not granted faith.
This is different.
True.
We heard the shahada from Sofia.
My heart knows.
I know, that snake is playing a game again but...
But it is the Prophet's sunnah.
We can't take her heart
out and check what is inside.
Only Allah knows if her
intention is sincere or not.
Will we forgive her now?
Father, isn't she going to
pay for all the things she did?
If she really believed..
...then it means Sofia died anyway.
She may been born again without a sin.
When my Allah gives new life to those
who repent, how can we stand against that?
But we must be careful until
we are sure she is not lying.
Of course. Of course, we will do that.
We will take all measures to
find out if she tells the truth or lies.
But until then, she will stay in the caged tent.
She will live according
to the rules of Islamic law.
My Bey, can I come in?
Come in.
My Bey, all Beys are here as you ordered.
We are ready for the council.
Attention!
Osman Bey the ruler!
Peace be upon you.
Peace be upon you too.
My Beys.
My sisters.
My Alps.
On the path we took with Turkishness
as our body and Islam as our soul...
...we never stopped fighting
to bring an order to the world.
Whenever we saw the tears of the oppressed
we were always worried about them.
We helped them, thank Allah.
Thank Allah.
We defeated many infidels,
and we were defeated by many.
But we never stayed back from war.
We expanded our lands.
We conquered many castles.
We conquered these castles to spread justice.
And now..
...the time has come to give these castles to
the reliable Beys whose justice will not fail.
Boran.
Koca Bey, come here.
Goynuk is under your command.
Rule with justice.
You give the orders and I obey, my Bey.
I will just look after what is yours.
Thank you, thank you.
Have a seat, Koca Bey.
Hasan Bey, come here.
Mudurnu is under your command. Rule with merit.
My Bey, I will rule Mudurnu
with justice and mercy.
-Thank you.
-Thank you. Have a seat.
Well, Alaaddin...
Come here, son.
My Bey.
The castle of Akhisar will have the
honor of having a Shahzade's justice.
Son, the castle of Akhisar is yours.
What my Beys points out, my
cause, is my most precious treasure.
Thank you, my Bey.
You're welcome.
Hristo, come here.
Well... Some never wake up
from the sleep of the wrong.
But you found the right way.
You will take care of the
Greek people in my lands.
Tell them about the justice of Kayi.
-May your duty be blessed.
-Thank you, Osman Bey.
I will tell all of them about the
love and mercy I saw in you.
Thank you.
Osman Bey, you have pleased all of us.
We were nomads. Thanks to you, we own lands now.
But I've heard the bad news.
They say the emperor is marching
towards us with all his strength.
Let him come.
We are a high plane tree.
We won't fall with wind.
Let them come.
We have enough land to
bury them all, thank Allah.
Thank Allah.
My old heart wonders something, Osman Bey.
You said everything except our new target.
Tell us where to ride.
My Beys whose hearts are full of faith!
The new target isn't only a place...
...but all the lands where the sun descends!
I swear to Allah that I will
never stop fighting for this cause.
Allah is the greatest!
Forgive me, Allah
You remember the prayers only now, Sofia?
Allah..
There is nothing to do for me but praying, Bala.
Do you remember only when your way ends?
The biggest punishment for people...
...is staying alone with themselves, Bala.
I don't believe you, Sofia
Will you pretend to be a believer
and start causing unrest again?
I've just realized that I have nothing but Poena.
I mean Halime.
I know.
I know that even she isn't mine.
For the first time I'm unmasked.
Sofia.
Bala.
Today, for the first time, I saw
Allah inside me Who you believed in.
Will He accept me?
Will He forgive me, Bala?
Forgiving isn't up to us, but to Allah.
I can't measure your words,
but your intention.
My intention is real.
I don't seek vengeance but a path.
I know you will never forgive me.
But I need your guidance.
Bala.
Will you help me?
In the name of Allah,
the merciful, the compassionate.
Come on. Here we go!
O my nation!
Since the day when the
truth called out from Hira Mountain,
...we have never
abandoned the right way.
We haven't gone beyond the
way our Prophet opened.
The plane tree growing up in my chest
became a dream of conquest for us.
We stood ready for cruelty, torture and defeats.
We wanted the Islam world
to be united and strong.
In this era where the hopes
are growing, I have an oath.
We'll spread the words of
Allah in more seas and lands.
Wherever an innocent cries,
we'll arise there like a thunderbolt!
And we will shout out to the whole world.
Justice forever.
Freedom forever.